<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Motorbike App</string>

    <string name = "Meteor350">
        This brand-new-for-2021 addition from now Indian-owned Royal Enfield looks set to be one of the cruiser bargains of the year – and we say ‘set’ to be because, as we write, we’ve not actually ridden it yet, with the Meteor 350 due to be released in Spring 2021. From what we do know, however, it looks to be temptingly different. It’s aimed at novices and commuters, is powered by a fairly soft, 350cc single cylinder engine that’s A2 licence compliant, has a laid back, cruiser-style twin shock chassis and will come with a three-year warranty along with three years roadside assistance as standard. Most impressive of all, though, is the price.
    </string>
    <string name = "CMX500Rebel">
        Honda’s cruiser version of its A2-licence-friendly, budget-price, 500cc twin family (the others being the CB500F roadster, CBR500F sportster and CB500X adventure bike) is the equally novice-friendly CMX500. With its similar 471cc parallel twin detuned to an even more flexible and idiot-proof 45bhp plus new frame (with more rake and an even lower seat) it’s even less intimidating than its siblings yet is surprisingly eager and good fun to zip around on, too. The looks may not be to everyone’s taste (Honda never has been very good at ‘doing a Harley’) but it’s customizable, good value, is Euro5 compliant and ticks a lot of boxes.
    </string>
    <string name= "VulcanS">
        Often cruelly overlooked middleweight is based on the ER-6n (now Z650) parallel twin engine and is a temptingly affordable, easy to get on with all-rounder. The seat’s a usefully low 705mm; the engine produces a more than adequate 60bhp and it’s also light, manageable, comfortable and reliable. The Vulcan make lack the authenticity of a Triumph or Harley and the class and grunt of bigger machines but it more than makes up for it with friendly accessibility and great value.
    </string>
    <string name = "CMX1100Rebel">
        Another newcomer for 2021 is Honda’s all-new ‘bigger brother’ to its popular CMX500 Rebel – the CMX1100. Inspired by and styled very much like the junior, novice version, the bigger Rebel is also powered by a parallel twin cylinder engine, but this time a detuned but still 86bhp version of the unit from the Africa Twin adventure bike. Elsewhere it also follows the design cues of the 500 but scaled and specced up accordingly. The brakes are bigger, the suspension larger, the LED headlight and clocks more sophisticated. There’s also four switchable riding modes and the option of Honda’s slick, semi-automatic ‘DCT’ gearbox (for £900 more) and yet the whole bike still has a reassuring low saddle, should be a doddle to ride and is temptingly affordable, too.
    </string>
    <string name = "Scout1200">
        When the (mostly) dormant historic US Indian brand was snapped up by the giant, Victory-owning Polaris Industries in 2011 no-one predicted the sensation that would soon follow. The first bike, the big, V-twin engine Chief came within two years and justifiably rattled American rival Harley. But Indian’s more entry-level, 1200cc Sportster rival, the Scout, was arguably even more impressive still. Powered by an all-new, 100bhp, liquid-cooled V-twin, with neat Art Deco styling and low, easy and engaging handling, the Scout can run rings around the Harley and in some ways is closer to a Ducati Monster than the US cruiser. On the downside, though, the Indian is at a significantly higher price point, too. But as an option between, say, the now deleted 883 Sportster and a genuine Big Twin, the Scout has lots of authentic American appeal. (A 999cc/78bhp version, the Scout Sixty, introduced in 2016, is instead a closer Sportster rival at £10,499, while there’s now also a Bobber version, too.)
    </string>
    <string name = "SoftailSlim">
        The big twin American has long been considered the most aspirational if not definitive V-twin cruiser in all its various forms – after all, Harley effectively invented the factory cruiser with its first Super Glide back in 1971. For many years, however, they’ve also been rightfully criticized for their old tech and limited performance. Improving in recent years, H-D’s cruisers made a quantum leap up for 2018 with its all-new ‘Softail’ family which replaced all the old Softails and Dynas with a new, lightweight, more rigid, monoshock chassis, uprated, 86bhp Milwaukee Eight engines, revised brakes, new styling and lots of modern detail touches such as LED lighting. Which grabs your fancy from the nine-strong family, ranging from the Low Rider to the monster Fat Boy, is down to personal taste, but the Softail Slim possibly satisfies most for its blend of ‘40s styling, punchy performance, distance practicality and impressive handling while the pared-down, basic Softail Standard, introduced in 2020, is now its most affordable big cruiser, at just £12,995.
    </string>
    <string name = "XDiavel">
        Possibly more of a hot rod, if the truth be told, than a classic cruiser, the Diavel, simply rewrote the performance cruiser rule book when first launched in 2011 thanks to its mix of 160bhp Testastretta superbike power, cutting edge electronics and cycle parts and class-defying handling – but then, being a Ducati, perhaps we shouldn’t have expected anything less. The longer, lower, more feet-forward X-Diavel from 2016 took things even more cruiser-ey and is a fabulous machine, especially in higher spec ‘S’ form. It’s not for novices, is not cheap and is certainly not for traditional cruiser types, but the X-Diavel is a phenomenal machine and a true cat among the conventional cruiser pigeon.
    </string>
    <string name = "R18">
        It’s probably fair to say that BMW didn’t quite get it right with its last attempt at a cruiser, the awkwardly-styled R1200C of 1998 through to 2003 but the Bavarian marque has more than made amends with this all-new offering, launched in 2020. Aimed very much at American Harley buyers and drawing inspiration from both US cruiser style and BMW’s heritage, the R18 is all new from the ground up. At its heart is a massive, all-new, air-cooled classic boxer twin that pushes out a Harley-esque 90bhp along with plenty of torque. There’s an exposed, old-style shaft drive, three riding modes, fabulous black and chrome styling inspired by BMW’s R5 of 1936 and the amount of glorious detailing and quality touches you’d expect of a bike at this price. A genuine Harley rival but with the classy touches, quality (and price) you’d expect of a BMW. Oh, and if that’s not enough, there’s also a screen and panniered ‘bagger’ Classic version available, for £20,980.
    </string>
    <string name = "Rocket3">
        Another all-new monster cruiser introduced in 2020 – although Triumph itself calls its new Rocket3 a ‘muscle roadster’. Either way, the Rocket3 simply can’t be ignored. An all-new successor to Triumph’s original 2300cc triple of 2004, the new version has an all-new, 2458cc engine producing a massive 1665bhp plus a Tarmac-shredding 163ft-lb of torque, monster hot rod performance unequalled by any other machine. But arguably even more impressive are the new Rocket’s manageable handling and practicality, thanks to a superb chassis, electronic rider aids, switchable riding modes, top notch brakes and more, which all combine to keep that size and performance under control. Two versions are available, the standard ‘R’ and the more tourer GT with small screen, pillion backrest and more, but neither are remotely basic. The Rocket3 may be more monster hot rod than laid back cruiser, but if you want a bike of this style that has the most, you can’t ignore it.
    </string>
    <string name = "VintageDarkHorse">
        Reborn Indian’s big cruiser V-twins are possibly the grandest and most glorious traditional cruisers of all – and certainly among the most expensive. Ranging from the basic cruiser Vintage to the ‘bagger’ Chieftain and Springfield, to the ‘full-dresser’ Roadmaster, and with prices ranging from 18 to £30K, all tick virtually all the cruiser boxes. Engines are the same glorious ‘Thunderstroke’ 1811cc V-twin (although Indian also recently introduced its new water-cooled Challenger); their chassis share decent cycle parts (enough to inspire a raft of Harley updates since) and style, detailing, comfort and quality are all first rate. The Vintage has replaced the Chief as Indian’s basic cruisers and, with its classic Indian flared fender and with the Dark Horse version’s pure, naked stance, it’s Indian’s purest cruiser – American V-twin cruisers don’t get bolder, better or classier.
    </string>

    <string name = "Interceptor650">
        The Interceptor is the sister bike to Royal Enfield’s Continental GT with the former being a Triumph Bonneville-rivalling retro roadster, the latter a café racer-styled spin-ff. Both share the same air-cooled, 648cc, 47bhp twin, a Harris Performance-designed tubular steel twin loop frame and cycle parts including wire wheels, disc brakes and telescopic fork/twin shock suspension.\n\n
        The sporty Continental GT has lower, café racer style clip-ons, slimmer, smaller tank (complete with ‘Monza’ filler cap) and optional single racer seat while the roadster Interceptor has upright, one-piece bars and a bigger and more bulbous tank.\n\n
        The all-new engine is willing, thrummy and A2-compliant, the handling is sweet and easy. Build and equipment is adequate rather than inspiring, but the look is great, the experience easy and evocative and the value, thanks to being built in India, incontestable. For this look and badge, nothing at this price comes close, no wonder both have proved big hits.
    </string>
    <string name = "XSR700">
        Yamaha’s two XSRs are the retro-restyled versions of its popular and perky MT-07/MT-09 modular roadsters. The 847cc, 115bhp, three-cylinder MT-09 came first in 2013 and proved an instant hit for its combination of fun and value, with the twin cylinder, 74bhp, 689cc MT-07 version coming a year later and becoming a Europe-wide best-seller ever since. But if they could be criticised for anything it was for their slightly basic spec and oddball looks. Enter the XSRs in 2016. Both got retro-inspired restyles (although they’re still quirky rather than conventional) with different lights, alloy tank, seat and even ‘retro’ Pirelli Phantom tyres, yet will all the same perky practicality as before. Suspension on the 700 isn’t the best but it’s still great value, lively, practical and now, good looking as well. The 900, meanwhile, is £9699.
    </string>
    <string name= "V7Sport">
        The V7 is to Italy what Triumph’s Bonnie is to Britain – yet with arguably even more authenticity. A similarly styled and proportioned roadster, the V7 was introduced in ‘Classic’ form in 2007 and gone on through various evolutions since to become the historic Italian marque’s bedrock and one of its biggest success stories. It’s been updated again, like many others, for 2021, primarily to comply with the new Euro5 regulations, with the biggest change being the new 850cc engine from the V850TT adventure bike, which is also usefully more powerful, now putting out a claimed 65bhp. But there are changes elsewhere, too including new instruments, seat, and a subtle styling revision.\n\n
        Three models are now available: the base, entry-level, blacked-out Stone, from £8000; the uprated, more chrome-laden Special (pictured), with twin clocks and more convincing retro styling from £8600 and the limited-edition Stone Centenario, to marks Guzzi’s 2021 centenary, from £8200. No longer underpowered compared to the 900 Bonneville it offers a lot of charm and authenticity at an even more tempting price.
    </string>
    <string name = "StreetTwin">
        British marque Triumph has been class-leaders when it comes to retro roadster, ever since it reinvented its Bonneville way back in 2001. The classically-styled but easy-going twin has been a best-seller ever since, has been repeatedly updated – most significantly in 2016 – and all have received a major refresh for 2021 – including the entry-level, most affordable Street Twin.\n\n
        Based around the smaller, easier-going 900cc version of the Bonneville engine, this unit has not been revised to meet Euro5 but also gets a useful 10bhp power boost taking peak power from 54 to 64bhp while other engine changes, including a lighter clutch, help reduce the T100’s overall weight by 4kg. It also gets an uprated Brembo brake caliper and front forks, refreshed instruments, new cast wheels, a more comfortable, 10mm thicker bench seat and revised bodywork and detailing including side panels with mesh detailing. As an affordable, authentic, and still quality entry into retro roadsters, they don’t get much better.
    </string>
    <string name = "CB1100EX">
        Unique among the retro roadster breed, the big CB1100 is also typically Honda in being a clean-sheet, technological tour de force – in this case an air-cooled transverse four, something Honda hadn’t built for 30 years and one that is a huge achievement. It took even Honda a while to get it right, though. First seen as a concept bike in 2009, then an Australasia/Japan special it finally came to UK in 2013. Although its engine, in particular, was admired, that version was also considered a little bland with niggly details such as a too-small tank. Other revisions followed and finally, for 2017, with new tank, revised intake/exhaust (for a more characterful delivery) plus a new, sportier and’80s-styled RS sister model (at £200 more), it’s now classy, authentic and uber-cool. Still a little soft and no powerhouse, and likely to not be around due to Euro5 after current stocks sell out, the CB is also cultured and satisfying.
    </string>
    <string name = "Z900RS">
        An impressive hit due to its combination of mouth-watering, Z1-inspired styling – right down to its twin clocks, clever alloy wheels (which remind of wires) and ‘70s brown/orange livery – on top of already potent, 110bhp Z900 running gear, the RS is one of the best Japanese retros yet. Its Z900 chassis and liquid-cooled four means it’s a decent performer and there are enough sweet styling touches to satisfy. The only downside? Annoyingly, the Z1-alike green or brown colours cost £300 more.
    </string>
    <string name = "BonnevilleT120">
        Revived British icon Triumph know more than most about producing successful retro roadsters having introduced its first modern Bonneville way back in 2000 (although the retro styled but modern engineered 900 Thunderbird goes back even further to 1995), so it’s no wonder the latest T100 (900cc) and T120 (1200cc) Bonnevilles, which have just been improved again for 2021, are pretty much the definitive examples of the breed. In short, if you want a pleasing roadster with modern mechanicals and classic ‘50s/’60s British twin style, the Bonnevilles have it all: idiot-proof manners; pleasing performance; great styling and detailing (these are no ‘dressed up’ bikes like the SV/XSR/Z900, but have dedicated engines, chassis and more) and, best of all, the right tank badge. Although the £10,800, 1200cc, 79bhp T120 is undoubtedly the better bike and ‘more’ in every way, but the T100 900 has a lot going for it, too, has just received a 10bhp power boost, so offering enough performance for most, but costs £1700 less.
    </string>
    <string name = "RnineTPure">
        Triumph’s Bonneville aside, BM’s R nineT retro roadster, first introduced in 2014 as a short-run anniversary special, is arguably the bike that most fuelled the growth of the retro roadster category. Basically, a modern R1200R roadster (which uses the older, oil-cooled, 110bhp version of BM’s boxer 1200 powertrain) but with retro-inspired styling touches that pay homage to great BMW boxers of yore, that bike proved such a hit for its blend of modern manners, 120mph performance and classy, heritage style, that it spawned a whole family of spin-offs and rivals. The ‘Pure’ was added in 2018 as the most affordable, bare bones variant (thanks to cast not wire wheels, steel (not ali) tank plus more basic suspension) while other current versions include the original, high spec R nineT, R nineT Scrambler and R nineT Urban G/S. All have been updated for Euro5 and are classy, versatile all-rounders with just the right level of retro style. But the Pure is the best value of all.
    </string>
    <string name = "FTR">
        Upstart American manufacturer and great Harley rival Indian have come up with some great bikes since its relaunch in 2014, but one of the greatest – and biggest surprises, to boot – was its flat-track styled, retro roadster, the FTR1200, in 2019. Based on a tuned version of the 1200cc Scout V-twin, it produced a lively 118bhp and its flat-track-style chassis was both a great-looking, different take on the retro theme yet also handled well and was hugely entertaining. Think of it as an American Ducati Monster and you won’t be far wrong. It even came in three different versions – the standard bike, a semi-off-road ‘Rally, higher spec ‘S’ with extra electronics and cosmetic touches and a top-of-the-range Carbon with fancy suspension, bodywork and more. In fact, the only thing wrong with any of them was slightly odd wheel sizes, 19in front and 18in rear, which limited tyre choice. That’s now been remedied for 2021 (it now has 17inchers front and rear) making it certainly one of the best performing – and quirkily different looking – retro roadsters of all.
    </string>
    <string name = "Scrambler1100SportPro">
        The Italian legend’s ‘Scrambler’ sub-brand of retro-styled, novice-friendly V-twins have proved a huge success ever since the first four 800cc models were introduced in 2015. An A2 licence compliant 400cc version came in 2016, while some other stylized versions followed, although all were considered slightly tame. But its 1100cc models, first introduced in 2018, brought slightly larger proportions, decently meaty 86bhp performance and more – yet all with the pleasing retro Scrambler style. The latest versions have been revised again with an improved rear end, Euro5 compliance, new exhaust and more and comprise the 1100 Pro, 1100 Dark Pro and top-of-the-range 1100 Sport Pro featuring quality Öhlins suspension, an aggressive riding position and decent electronics including three riding modes. It’s a brilliant handler, has lots of Ducati retro kudos and is good fun, but its 85bhp is a little bit lacking considering the hefty price.
    </string>

    <string name = "RS125GPReplica">
        When you’re 17 and only qualify only for an A1-compliant 15bhp 125, a sports bike has a slightly different meaning with styling and kudos triumphing but with usability and affordability being important, too. But although Yamaha’s best-selling R125 remains popular, the ultimate ‘poster bike’ for this generation is surely Italian marque Aprilia’s gorgeous RS 125. Effectively the Ducati of the 125 class, the RS built its reputation in the ‘90s on a screaming, 125GP-alike two-stroke engine with the aluminium twin beam frame, cycle parts and styling to match. And although since 2011 Euro regulations have forced it to switch to more muted, four-stroke power, its RSV4-alike styling, quality brakes and suspension and GP heritage means it’s still the one most lust after. Today a new RS 125 will set you back £4499, but the GP Replica, for £100 more, comes in full MotoGP-alike livery.
    </string>
    <string name = "RC390">
        Arguably the rawest, purest, most focused A2-compliant sportster of all, the RC 390 is a simple, lightweight, compact single-cylinder sportster inspired by the Austrian firm’s Moto3 race bike and based on the powertrain and running gear of its lively, looney 390 Duke. As such it’s small, focused – and fabulous fun, as long as you’re fairly small and like your thrills in short doses. Its 44bhp single, though not as thrilling as a ‘multi’, has enough to beat ‘the ton’ but it’s the sharp, lightweight chassis and braking performance where the RC truly stands out – very few bikes are as nimble, lively or engaging through medium speed twisties. Plus, being so light and small means the RC is also about as unintimidating as sports bikes get for novice riders, too. Not cheap, and it’s so basic you do wonder a little where your money’s going, but it’s still one of the best.
    </string>
    <string name = "Ninja650">
        Once you’ve qualified for your full licence the idea of moving straight to a 150bhp+, litre-class superbike can be more than a little intimidating – which is where newcomer-friendly, middleweight sportsters like the Ninja 650 come in. Introduced in 2017 then updated and refreshed in 2020, it’s a fully updated version of the old ER6f and as such is based around the familiar, willing and free-revving 649cc parallel twin that dominates Minitwin racing, particularly in the renamed Junior TT. Reworked to produce a useful 67bhp it’s now held in a lighter, Ninja H2-inspired tubular steel chassis with new rear suspension, twin wavy discs and racy, all-new bodywork that’s a kind of mix between Kawasaki’s ZX-10R and the Ninja H2. The overall result looks great, is decently equipped, light, nimble and upright enough to be an absolute doddle to ride, reasonably versatile and yet great fun to thrash and brilliant looking as well. As a stepping-stone to 100bhp+ sports bikes there are few better
    </string>
    <string name = "RS660">
        Aprilia’s all new RS660 is a revelation. A 100bhp middleweight twin that’s effectively ‘half’ the V4 from the RSV4 1100 V4, it succeeds in being both a genuine, classy and enjoyable road sportster yet is also one that’s affordable and accessible for relative novices. With a short wheelbase, sharp steering geometry, light weight and quality suspension it handles brilliantly. Yet it’s also surprisingly relaxed and comfortable with excellent ‘real world’ ergonomics. The new engine is great fun to thrash, sounds good, is responsive and blessed with excellent fuelling and a synchronized quick-shifter. While the bonus is, when you look down at the full colour TFT dash, you’re not doubling the speed limit and facing a jail sentence should you get caught. The RS660 is reasonably quick, I’d estimate top speed is around 140mph, but unlike a RSV4 not scary on the road. The overall result is a versatile, fun and desirable bike for inexperienced and experienced riders alike and a comfortable and unintimidating road bike with a typically Aprilia sporting edge.
    </string>
    <string name = "S1000RR">
        Ten years on from the original, game-changing S1000RR, BMW have come up with an all-new, third generation model that has not only finally got rid of the controversial asymmetrical headlights but was better in every way. More powerful (now with a giddy 204bhp), lighter, sharper-steering and more sophisticated BMW’s new flagship is also, even more surprisingly, easier to ride, more roomy, comfortable and reassuring, as well. Never the cheapest, yet to succeed in WSB and admittedly facing fierce competition from the likes of not just Ducatis’ V4 Panigale but also Honda’s latest Fireblade and the newly-updated (and WSB-dominating) Kawasaki ZX-10R, the BMW stands out not just for its brute power and dynamism, but even more for its real world road manners, prestige badge, classy dealer network and decent residuals. Besides, if you want more there’s also BMW’s traditional long list of accessories and even a new M1000RR version.
    </string>
    <string name = "ZX10R">
        Kawasaki’s ZX-10R has been the world superbikes track king pretty much since this latest, ‘point’ version, complete with 197bhp and a track-attitude like no other, was launched in 2011 then continually evolved since. If you wanted a track-ready, rev-hungry, electronics-laden racer-replica, the ZX-10R was the one – as has been proven by its seven world superbike titles, including six-in-a-row for Ulsterman Jonathan Rea since. For 2021, thanks to an aerodynamically-driven facelift and other subtle mods, it promises to be even better still while true track fiends have the option to go further still with the RR version, complete with lightweight Marchesini forged wheels, titanium engine parts and more, for a whopping £24,799. If you want the closest thing there is to a proven superbike king, this is it.
    </string>
    <string name = "GSXR1000R">
        Suzuki had been one of the ‘big hitters’ in the 1000cc superbike class, ever since its introduction of the class-leading first GSX-R1000K1 in 2001. However, despite subsequent highs such as the 2005 K5 version, the GSX-R fell away slightly from 2007, becoming larger and heavier – and by so doing remaining a great road bike – and less competitive on track. All of which made the arrival of an all-new, MotoGP-inspired ‘Gixxer in 2017 big news. Two versions were available, a base, bargain-priced GSX-R which has niow been dropped, and this ‘R’ version complete with variable valve timing and higher spec cycle parts that grabbed most of the headlines and won that year’s Senior TT with Michael Dunlop.
    </string>
    <string name = "YZFR1">
        Yamaha’s legendary R1 has been at the top of the Japanese superbikes tree ever since the original rewrote the class rules with its whopping 150bhp but ultra light weight in 1998. Repeatedly updated over five distinct versions since, this latest-generation, MotoGP M1-alike version debuted in 2015, characterised by diminutive GP looks, whopping 197bhp power and sophisticated electronics. In truth, it had started to fall behind the pack once again, particularly the class leaders from Ducati, BMW and Kawasaki, but a 2020 updated and refresh improved the looks and made it Euro5 compliant without compromising its 197bhp peak power. Its dash may not quite match the latest big screen colour TFTs from the likes of the S1000RR and V4 Panigale and it remains compact and extreme, but the latest R1, especially in higher spec, semi-active Ohlins suspension-equipped R1-M form (costing £22,599) arguably remains the closest thing to a Japanese MotoGP bike you can buy – and who doesn’t fancy at playing at being Rossi?
    </string>
    <string name = "CBR1000RRRFireblade">
        After a decade in the superbike doldrums and the false promise of an all-new 2017 offering that had neither the raw power to upset the elite nor electronics sophisticated enough to compensate for it, the legendary Fireblade was finally back with a bang in 2020. Derived from Honda’s MotoGP expertise, with 201bhp, sorted electronics and sharper and racier than ever, it contrasts with previous recent ‘Blades by being totally focussed on winning on the track – which it has already made a decent fist of. The downside of that, of course, is, (like most superbikes, to be honest) it makes little practical sense on the road, is extreme and can be annoying. Revvier than most, without the ShiftCam-supplied grunt of BMW’s latest S1000RR, the latest Blade requires you to forget that previous examples also had a flexibility and comfort that made then great road bikes. But as a track weapon, this latest Fireblade is the sharpest yet.
    </string>
    <string name = "PanigaleV4S">
        Revolutionary bikes don’t come along that often in the superbike class. Going back to the early 1990s there was the original Honda CBR900RR FireBlade, followed by Ducati’s 916 in 1994. The first R1 in 1998 was followed by the first GSX-R1000 in 2001. But this, Ducati’s all-new V4 replacement for its long-line of class-leading V-twins, is up there with all of them. First there’s its significance: a V4 in place of Ducati’s V-twin heritage. Then there’s its specification: a class-leading 214bhp at the crank, which translates into an equally class-leading 198bhp at the rear wheel; a peerless chassis slathered with semi-active Ohlins (in this S form, the base model does without), the very latest Brembo Stylema calipers, Marchesini wheels and class-leading electronics, all controlled via a flash, full-colour TFT display. But best of all is how it all works and goes – and that’s simply like nothing else. Most superbikes are capable of taking your breath away, the Panigale V4 does it in every way – its look, spec, ability performance and, yes, at nearly £25K, its price, too. But boy is it worth it.
    </string>

</resources>