<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Motorbike App</string>

    <string name = "Meteor350">
        This brand-new-for-2021 addition from now Indian-owned Royal Enfield looks set to be one of the cruiser bargains of the year – and we say ‘set’ to be because, as we write, we’ve not actually ridden it yet, with the Meteor 350 due to be released in Spring 2021. From what we do know, however, it looks to be temptingly different. It’s aimed at novices and commuters, is powered by a fairly soft, 350cc single cylinder engine that’s A2 licence compliant, has a laid back, cruiser-style twin shock chassis and will come with a three-year warranty along with three years roadside assistance as standard. Most impressive of all, though, is the price.
    </string>
    <string name = "CMX500Rebel">
        Honda’s cruiser version of its A2-licence-friendly, budget-price, 500cc twin family (the others being the CB500F roadster, CBR500F sportster and CB500X adventure bike) is the equally novice-friendly CMX500. With its similar 471cc parallel twin detuned to an even more flexible and idiot-proof 45bhp plus new frame (with more rake and an even lower seat) it’s even less intimidating than its siblings yet is surprisingly eager and good fun to zip around on, too. The looks may not be to everyone’s taste (Honda never has been very good at ‘doing a Harley’) but it’s customizable, good value, is Euro5 compliant and ticks a lot of boxes.
    </string>
    <string name= "VulcanS">
        Often cruelly overlooked middleweight is based on the ER-6n (now Z650) parallel twin engine and is a temptingly affordable, easy to get on with all-rounder. The seat’s a usefully low 705mm; the engine produces a more than adequate 60bhp and it’s also light, manageable, comfortable and reliable. The Vulcan make lack the authenticity of a Triumph or Harley and the class and grunt of bigger machines but it more than makes up for it with friendly accessibility and great value.
    </string>
    <string name = "CMX1100Rebel">
        Another newcomer for 2021 is Honda’s all-new ‘bigger brother’ to its popular CMX500 Rebel – the CMX1100. Inspired by and styled very much like the junior, novice version, the bigger Rebel is also powered by a parallel twin cylinder engine, but this time a detuned but still 86bhp version of the unit from the Africa Twin adventure bike. Elsewhere it also follows the design cues of the 500 but scaled and specced up accordingly. The brakes are bigger, the suspension larger, the LED headlight and clocks more sophisticated. There’s also four switchable riding modes and the option of Honda’s slick, semi-automatic ‘DCT’ gearbox (for £900 more) and yet the whole bike still has a reassuring low saddle, should be a doddle to ride and is temptingly affordable, too.
    </string>
    <string name = "Scout1200">
        When the (mostly) dormant historic US Indian brand was snapped up by the giant, Victory-owning Polaris Industries in 2011 no-one predicted the sensation that would soon follow. The first bike, the big, V-twin engine Chief came within two years and justifiably rattled American rival Harley. But Indian’s more entry-level, 1200cc Sportster rival, the Scout, was arguably even more impressive still. Powered by an all-new, 100bhp, liquid-cooled V-twin, with neat Art Deco styling and low, easy and engaging handling, the Scout can run rings around the Harley and in some ways is closer to a Ducati Monster than the US cruiser. On the downside, though, the Indian is at a significantly higher price point, too. But as an option between, say, the now deleted 883 Sportster and a genuine Big Twin, the Scout has lots of authentic American appeal. (A 999cc/78bhp version, the Scout Sixty, introduced in 2016, is instead a closer Sportster rival at £10,499, while there’s now also a Bobber version, too.)
    </string>
    <string name = "SoftailSlim">
        The big twin American has long been considered the most aspirational if not definitive V-twin cruiser in all its various forms – after all, Harley effectively invented the factory cruiser with its first Super Glide back in 1971. For many years, however, they’ve also been rightfully criticized for their old tech and limited performance. Improving in recent years, H-D’s cruisers made a quantum leap up for 2018 with its all-new ‘Softail’ family which replaced all the old Softails and Dynas with a new, lightweight, more rigid, monoshock chassis, uprated, 86bhp Milwaukee Eight engines, revised brakes, new styling and lots of modern detail touches such as LED lighting. Which grabs your fancy from the nine-strong family, ranging from the Low Rider to the monster Fat Boy, is down to personal taste, but the Softail Slim possibly satisfies most for its blend of ‘40s styling, punchy performance, distance practicality and impressive handling while the pared-down, basic Softail Standard, introduced in 2020, is now its most affordable big cruiser, at just £12,995.
    </string>
    <string name = "XDiavel">
        Possibly more of a hot rod, if the truth be told, than a classic cruiser, the Diavel, simply rewrote the performance cruiser rule book when first launched in 2011 thanks to its mix of 160bhp Testastretta superbike power, cutting edge electronics and cycle parts and class-defying handling – but then, being a Ducati, perhaps we shouldn’t have expected anything less. The longer, lower, more feet-forward X-Diavel from 2016 took things even more cruiser-ey and is a fabulous machine, especially in higher spec ‘S’ form. It’s not for novices, is not cheap and is certainly not for traditional cruiser types, but the X-Diavel is a phenomenal machine and a true cat among the conventional cruiser pigeon.
    </string>
    <string name = "R18">
        It’s probably fair to say that BMW didn’t quite get it right with its last attempt at a cruiser, the awkwardly-styled R1200C of 1998 through to 2003 but the Bavarian marque has more than made amends with this all-new offering, launched in 2020. Aimed very much at American Harley buyers and drawing inspiration from both US cruiser style and BMW’s heritage, the R18 is all new from the ground up. At its heart is a massive, all-new, air-cooled classic boxer twin that pushes out a Harley-esque 90bhp along with plenty of torque. There’s an exposed, old-style shaft drive, three riding modes, fabulous black and chrome styling inspired by BMW’s R5 of 1936 and the amount of glorious detailing and quality touches you’d expect of a bike at this price. A genuine Harley rival but with the classy touches, quality (and price) you’d expect of a BMW. Oh, and if that’s not enough, there’s also a screen and panniered ‘bagger’ Classic version available, for £20,980.
    </string>
    <string name = "Rocket3">
        Another all-new monster cruiser introduced in 2020 – although Triumph itself calls its new Rocket3 a ‘muscle roadster’. Either way, the Rocket3 simply can’t be ignored. An all-new successor to Triumph’s original 2300cc triple of 2004, the new version has an all-new, 2458cc engine producing a massive 1665bhp plus a Tarmac-shredding 163ft-lb of torque, monster hot rod performance unequalled by any other machine. But arguably even more impressive are the new Rocket’s manageable handling and practicality, thanks to a superb chassis, electronic rider aids, switchable riding modes, top notch brakes and more, which all combine to keep that size and performance under control. Two versions are available, the standard ‘R’ and the more tourer GT with small screen, pillion backrest and more, but neither are remotely basic. The Rocket3 may be more monster hot rod than laid back cruiser, but if you want a bike of this style that has the most, you can’t ignore it.
    </string>
    <string name = "VintageDarkHorse">
        Reborn Indian’s big cruiser V-twins are possibly the grandest and most glorious traditional cruisers of all – and certainly among the most expensive. Ranging from the basic cruiser Vintage to the ‘bagger’ Chieftain and Springfield, to the ‘full-dresser’ Roadmaster, and with prices ranging from 18 to £30K, all tick virtually all the cruiser boxes. Engines are the same glorious ‘Thunderstroke’ 1811cc V-twin (although Indian also recently introduced its new water-cooled Challenger); their chassis share decent cycle parts (enough to inspire a raft of Harley updates since) and style, detailing, comfort and quality are all first rate. The Vintage has replaced the Chief as Indian’s basic cruisers and, with its classic Indian flared fender and with the Dark Horse version’s pure, naked stance, it’s Indian’s purest cruiser – American V-twin cruisers don’t get bolder, better or classier.
    </string>

    <string name = "Interceptor650">
        The Interceptor is the sister bike to Royal Enfield’s Continental GT with the former being a Triumph Bonneville-rivalling retro roadster, the latter a café racer-styled spin-ff. Both share the same air-cooled, 648cc, 47bhp twin, a Harris Performance-designed tubular steel twin loop frame and cycle parts including wire wheels, disc brakes and telescopic fork/twin shock suspension.\n\n
        The sporty Continental GT has lower, café racer style clip-ons, slimmer, smaller tank (complete with ‘Monza’ filler cap) and optional single racer seat while the roadster Interceptor has upright, one-piece bars and a bigger and more bulbous tank.\n\n
        The all-new engine is willing, thrummy and A2-compliant, the handling is sweet and easy. Build and equipment is adequate rather than inspiring, but the look is great, the experience easy and evocative and the value, thanks to being built in India, incontestable. For this look and badge, nothing at this price comes close, no wonder both have proved big hits.
    </string>
    <string name = "XSR700">
        Yamaha’s two XSRs are the retro-restyled versions of its popular and perky MT-07/MT-09 modular roadsters. The 847cc, 115bhp, three-cylinder MT-09 came first in 2013 and proved an instant hit for its combination of fun and value, with the twin cylinder, 74bhp, 689cc MT-07 version coming a year later and becoming a Europe-wide best-seller ever since. But if they could be criticised for anything it was for their slightly basic spec and oddball looks. Enter the XSRs in 2016. Both got retro-inspired restyles (although they’re still quirky rather than conventional) with different lights, alloy tank, seat and even ‘retro’ Pirelli Phantom tyres, yet will all the same perky practicality as before. Suspension on the 700 isn’t the best but it’s still great value, lively, practical and now, good looking as well. The 900, meanwhile, is £9699.
    </string>
    <string name= "V7Sport">
        The V7 is to Italy what Triumph’s Bonnie is to Britain – yet with arguably even more authenticity. A similarly styled and proportioned roadster, the V7 was introduced in ‘Classic’ form in 2007 and gone on through various evolutions since to become the historic Italian marque’s bedrock and one of its biggest success stories. It’s been updated again, like many others, for 2021, primarily to comply with the new Euro5 regulations, with the biggest change being the new 850cc engine from the V850TT adventure bike, which is also usefully more powerful, now putting out a claimed 65bhp. But there are changes elsewhere, too including new instruments, seat, and a subtle styling revision.\n\n
        Three models are now available: the base, entry-level, blacked-out Stone, from £8000; the uprated, more chrome-laden Special (pictured), with twin clocks and more convincing retro styling from £8600 and the limited-edition Stone Centenario, to marks Guzzi’s 2021 centenary, from £8200. No longer underpowered compared to the 900 Bonneville it offers a lot of charm and authenticity at an even more tempting price.
    </string>
    <string name = "StreetTwin">
        British marque Triumph has been class-leaders when it comes to retro roadster, ever since it reinvented its Bonneville way back in 2001. The classically-styled but easy-going twin has been a best-seller ever since, has been repeatedly updated – most significantly in 2016 – and all have received a major refresh for 2021 – including the entry-level, most affordable Street Twin.\n\n
        Based around the smaller, easier-going 900cc version of the Bonneville engine, this unit has not been revised to meet Euro5 but also gets a useful 10bhp power boost taking peak power from 54 to 64bhp while other engine changes, including a lighter clutch, help reduce the T100’s overall weight by 4kg. It also gets an uprated Brembo brake caliper and front forks, refreshed instruments, new cast wheels, a more comfortable, 10mm thicker bench seat and revised bodywork and detailing including side panels with mesh detailing. As an affordable, authentic, and still quality entry into retro roadsters, they don’t get much better.
    </string>
    <string name = "CB1100EX">
        Unique among the retro roadster breed, the big CB1100 is also typically Honda in being a clean-sheet, technological tour de force – in this case an air-cooled transverse four, something Honda hadn’t built for 30 years and one that is a huge achievement. It took even Honda a while to get it right, though. First seen as a concept bike in 2009, then an Australasia/Japan special it finally came to UK in 2013. Although its engine, in particular, was admired, that version was also considered a little bland with niggly details such as a too-small tank. Other revisions followed and finally, for 2017, with new tank, revised intake/exhaust (for a more characterful delivery) plus a new, sportier and’80s-styled RS sister model (at £200 more), it’s now classy, authentic and uber-cool. Still a little soft and no powerhouse, and likely to not be around due to Euro5 after current stocks sell out, the CB is also cultured and satisfying.
    </string>
    <string name = "Z900RS">
        An impressive hit due to its combination of mouth-watering, Z1-inspired styling – right down to its twin clocks, clever alloy wheels (which remind of wires) and ‘70s brown/orange livery – on top of already potent, 110bhp Z900 running gear, the RS is one of the best Japanese retros yet. Its Z900 chassis and liquid-cooled four means it’s a decent performer and there are enough sweet styling touches to satisfy. The only downside? Annoyingly, the Z1-alike green or brown colours cost £300 more.
    </string>
    <string name = "BonnevilleT120">
        Revived British icon Triumph know more than most about producing successful retro roadsters having introduced its first modern Bonneville way back in 2000 (although the retro styled but modern engineered 900 Thunderbird goes back even further to 1995), so it’s no wonder the latest T100 (900cc) and T120 (1200cc) Bonnevilles, which have just been improved again for 2021, are pretty much the definitive examples of the breed. In short, if you want a pleasing roadster with modern mechanicals and classic ‘50s/’60s British twin style, the Bonnevilles have it all: idiot-proof manners; pleasing performance; great styling and detailing (these are no ‘dressed up’ bikes like the SV/XSR/Z900, but have dedicated engines, chassis and more) and, best of all, the right tank badge. Although the £10,800, 1200cc, 79bhp T120 is undoubtedly the better bike and ‘more’ in every way, but the T100 900 has a lot going for it, too, has just received a 10bhp power boost, so offering enough performance for most, but costs £1700 less.
    </string>
    <string name = "RnineTPure">
        Triumph’s Bonneville aside, BM’s R nineT retro roadster, first introduced in 2014 as a short-run anniversary special, is arguably the bike that most fuelled the growth of the retro roadster category. Basically, a modern R1200R roadster (which uses the older, oil-cooled, 110bhp version of BM’s boxer 1200 powertrain) but with retro-inspired styling touches that pay homage to great BMW boxers of yore, that bike proved such a hit for its blend of modern manners, 120mph performance and classy, heritage style, that it spawned a whole family of spin-offs and rivals. The ‘Pure’ was added in 2018 as the most affordable, bare bones variant (thanks to cast not wire wheels, steel (not ali) tank plus more basic suspension) while other current versions include the original, high spec R nineT, R nineT Scrambler and R nineT Urban G/S. All have been updated for Euro5 and are classy, versatile all-rounders with just the right level of retro style. But the Pure is the best value of all.
    </string>
    <string name = "FTR">
        Upstart American manufacturer and great Harley rival Indian have come up with some great bikes since its relaunch in 2014, but one of the greatest – and biggest surprises, to boot – was its flat-track styled, retro roadster, the FTR1200, in 2019. Based on a tuned version of the 1200cc Scout V-twin, it produced a lively 118bhp and its flat-track-style chassis was both a great-looking, different take on the retro theme yet also handled well and was hugely entertaining. Think of it as an American Ducati Monster and you won’t be far wrong. It even came in three different versions – the standard bike, a semi-off-road ‘Rally, higher spec ‘S’ with extra electronics and cosmetic touches and a top-of-the-range Carbon with fancy suspension, bodywork and more. In fact, the only thing wrong with any of them was slightly odd wheel sizes, 19in front and 18in rear, which limited tyre choice. That’s now been remedied for 2021 (it now has 17inchers front and rear) making it certainly one of the best performing – and quirkily different looking – retro roadsters of all.
    </string>
    <string name = "Scrambler1100SportPro">
        The Italian legend’s ‘Scrambler’ sub-brand of retro-styled, novice-friendly V-twins have proved a huge success ever since the first four 800cc models were introduced in 2015. An A2 licence compliant 400cc version came in 2016, while some other stylized versions followed, although all were considered slightly tame. But its 1100cc models, first introduced in 2018, brought slightly larger proportions, decently meaty 86bhp performance and more – yet all with the pleasing retro Scrambler style. The latest versions have been revised again with an improved rear end, Euro5 compliance, new exhaust and more and comprise the 1100 Pro, 1100 Dark Pro and top-of-the-range 1100 Sport Pro featuring quality Öhlins suspension, an aggressive riding position and decent electronics including three riding modes. It’s a brilliant handler, has lots of Ducati retro kudos and is good fun, but its 85bhp is a little bit lacking considering the hefty price.
    </string>

    <string name = "RS125GPReplica">
        When you’re 17 and only qualify only for an A1-compliant 15bhp 125, a sports bike has a slightly different meaning with styling and kudos triumphing but with usability and affordability being important, too. But although Yamaha’s best-selling R125 remains popular, the ultimate ‘poster bike’ for this generation is surely Italian marque Aprilia’s gorgeous RS 125. Effectively the Ducati of the 125 class, the RS built its reputation in the ‘90s on a screaming, 125GP-alike two-stroke engine with the aluminium twin beam frame, cycle parts and styling to match. And although since 2011 Euro regulations have forced it to switch to more muted, four-stroke power, its RSV4-alike styling, quality brakes and suspension and GP heritage means it’s still the one most lust after. Today a new RS 125 will set you back £4499, but the GP Replica, for £100 more, comes in full MotoGP-alike livery.
    </string>
    <string name = "RC390">
        Arguably the rawest, purest, most focused A2-compliant sportster of all, the RC 390 is a simple, lightweight, compact single-cylinder sportster inspired by the Austrian firm’s Moto3 race bike and based on the powertrain and running gear of its lively, looney 390 Duke. As such it’s small, focused – and fabulous fun, as long as you’re fairly small and like your thrills in short doses. Its 44bhp single, though not as thrilling as a ‘multi’, has enough to beat ‘the ton’ but it’s the sharp, lightweight chassis and braking performance where the RC truly stands out – very few bikes are as nimble, lively or engaging through medium speed twisties. Plus, being so light and small means the RC is also about as unintimidating as sports bikes get for novice riders, too. Not cheap, and it’s so basic you do wonder a little where your money’s going, but it’s still one of the best.
    </string>
    <string name = "Ninja650">
        Once you’ve qualified for your full licence the idea of moving straight to a 150bhp+, litre-class superbike can be more than a little intimidating – which is where newcomer-friendly, middleweight sportsters like the Ninja 650 come in. Introduced in 2017 then updated and refreshed in 2020, it’s a fully updated version of the old ER6f and as such is based around the familiar, willing and free-revving 649cc parallel twin that dominates Minitwin racing, particularly in the renamed Junior TT. Reworked to produce a useful 67bhp it’s now held in a lighter, Ninja H2-inspired tubular steel chassis with new rear suspension, twin wavy discs and racy, all-new bodywork that’s a kind of mix between Kawasaki’s ZX-10R and the Ninja H2. The overall result looks great, is decently equipped, light, nimble and upright enough to be an absolute doddle to ride, reasonably versatile and yet great fun to thrash and brilliant looking as well. As a stepping-stone to 100bhp+ sports bikes there are few better
    </string>
    <string name = "RS660">
        Aprilia’s all new RS660 is a revelation. A 100bhp middleweight twin that’s effectively ‘half’ the V4 from the RSV4 1100 V4, it succeeds in being both a genuine, classy and enjoyable road sportster yet is also one that’s affordable and accessible for relative novices. With a short wheelbase, sharp steering geometry, light weight and quality suspension it handles brilliantly. Yet it’s also surprisingly relaxed and comfortable with excellent ‘real world’ ergonomics. The new engine is great fun to thrash, sounds good, is responsive and blessed with excellent fuelling and a synchronized quick-shifter. While the bonus is, when you look down at the full colour TFT dash, you’re not doubling the speed limit and facing a jail sentence should you get caught. The RS660 is reasonably quick, I’d estimate top speed is around 140mph, but unlike a RSV4 not scary on the road. The overall result is a versatile, fun and desirable bike for inexperienced and experienced riders alike and a comfortable and unintimidating road bike with a typically Aprilia sporting edge.
    </string>
    <string name = "S1000RR">
        Ten years on from the original, game-changing S1000RR, BMW have come up with an all-new, third generation model that has not only finally got rid of the controversial asymmetrical headlights but was better in every way. More powerful (now with a giddy 204bhp), lighter, sharper-steering and more sophisticated BMW’s new flagship is also, even more surprisingly, easier to ride, more roomy, comfortable and reassuring, as well. Never the cheapest, yet to succeed in WSB and admittedly facing fierce competition from the likes of not just Ducatis’ V4 Panigale but also Honda’s latest Fireblade and the newly-updated (and WSB-dominating) Kawasaki ZX-10R, the BMW stands out not just for its brute power and dynamism, but even more for its real world road manners, prestige badge, classy dealer network and decent residuals. Besides, if you want more there’s also BMW’s traditional long list of accessories and even a new M1000RR version.
    </string>
    <string name = "ZX10R">
        Kawasaki’s ZX-10R has been the world superbikes track king pretty much since this latest, ‘point’ version, complete with 197bhp and a track-attitude like no other, was launched in 2011 then continually evolved since. If you wanted a track-ready, rev-hungry, electronics-laden racer-replica, the ZX-10R was the one – as has been proven by its seven world superbike titles, including six-in-a-row for Ulsterman Jonathan Rea since. For 2021, thanks to an aerodynamically-driven facelift and other subtle mods, it promises to be even better still while true track fiends have the option to go further still with the RR version, complete with lightweight Marchesini forged wheels, titanium engine parts and more, for a whopping £24,799. If you want the closest thing there is to a proven superbike king, this is it.
    </string>
    <string name = "GSXR1000R">
        Suzuki had been one of the ‘big hitters’ in the 1000cc superbike class, ever since its introduction of the class-leading first GSX-R1000K1 in 2001. However, despite subsequent highs such as the 2005 K5 version, the GSX-R fell away slightly from 2007, becoming larger and heavier – and by so doing remaining a great road bike – and less competitive on track. All of which made the arrival of an all-new, MotoGP-inspired ‘Gixxer in 2017 big news. Two versions were available, a base, bargain-priced GSX-R which has niow been dropped, and this ‘R’ version complete with variable valve timing and higher spec cycle parts that grabbed most of the headlines and won that year’s Senior TT with Michael Dunlop.
    </string>
    <string name = "YZFR1">
        Yamaha’s legendary R1 has been at the top of the Japanese superbikes tree ever since the original rewrote the class rules with its whopping 150bhp but ultra light weight in 1998. Repeatedly updated over five distinct versions since, this latest-generation, MotoGP M1-alike version debuted in 2015, characterised by diminutive GP looks, whopping 197bhp power and sophisticated electronics. In truth, it had started to fall behind the pack once again, particularly the class leaders from Ducati, BMW and Kawasaki, but a 2020 updated and refresh improved the looks and made it Euro5 compliant without compromising its 197bhp peak power. Its dash may not quite match the latest big screen colour TFTs from the likes of the S1000RR and V4 Panigale and it remains compact and extreme, but the latest R1, especially in higher spec, semi-active Ohlins suspension-equipped R1-M form (costing £22,599) arguably remains the closest thing to a Japanese MotoGP bike you can buy – and who doesn’t fancy at playing at being Rossi?
    </string>
    <string name = "CBR1000RRRFireblade">
        After a decade in the superbike doldrums and the false promise of an all-new 2017 offering that had neither the raw power to upset the elite nor electronics sophisticated enough to compensate for it, the legendary Fireblade was finally back with a bang in 2020. Derived from Honda’s MotoGP expertise, with 201bhp, sorted electronics and sharper and racier than ever, it contrasts with previous recent ‘Blades by being totally focussed on winning on the track – which it has already made a decent fist of. The downside of that, of course, is, (like most superbikes, to be honest) it makes little practical sense on the road, is extreme and can be annoying. Revvier than most, without the ShiftCam-supplied grunt of BMW’s latest S1000RR, the latest Blade requires you to forget that previous examples also had a flexibility and comfort that made then great road bikes. But as a track weapon, this latest Fireblade is the sharpest yet.
    </string>
    <string name = "PanigaleV4S">
        Revolutionary bikes don’t come along that often in the superbike class. Going back to the early 1990s there was the original Honda CBR900RR FireBlade, followed by Ducati’s 916 in 1994. The first R1 in 1998 was followed by the first GSX-R1000 in 2001. But this, Ducati’s all-new V4 replacement for its long-line of class-leading V-twins, is up there with all of them. First there’s its significance: a V4 in place of Ducati’s V-twin heritage. Then there’s its specification: a class-leading 214bhp at the crank, which translates into an equally class-leading 198bhp at the rear wheel; a peerless chassis slathered with semi-active Ohlins (in this S form, the base model does without), the very latest Brembo Stylema calipers, Marchesini wheels and class-leading electronics, all controlled via a flash, full-colour TFT display. But best of all is how it all works and goes – and that’s simply like nothing else. Most superbikes are capable of taking your breath away, the Panigale V4 does it in every way – its look, spec, ability performance and, yes, at nearly £25K, its price, too. But boy is it worth it.
    </string>

    <string name = "SV650">
        The long-lived and hugely popular Suzuki SV is the bike that kick-started the middleweight naked class when first launched way back in 1999. A simple but sweet-handling roadster (a half-faired S version was originally available as well) it was powered by a perky and flexible 69bhp 645cc V-twin. The result was an honest, affordable yet rewarding bike that was great for novices. Numerous reincarnations since led to a reintroduced SV in 2016, which has also been updated to be Euro5 compliant for 2021. The basic layout and appeal remain but despite updated looks and revised 72bhp motor, it now seems a little dated. Still great value, though.
    </string>
    <string name = "Z650">
        The Kawasaki Z650 has a long and popular lineage. Born as the ER-6n in 2005 clever design with an eye on costs produced an easy-to-ride yet invigorating middleweight that was a close rival for the Suzuki. A reinvention in 2017 saw a switch to the historic Zed name and trellis frame inspired by that of the supercharged H2 hyperbike. While another update for Euro5 in 2020 saw anther appealing styling tweak and the addition of a new, colour TFT dash. The result is more modern than the SV, is one of the most stylish, and best finished of budget middleweights, its ‘cuter’ dimensions suit smaller or more novice riders, yet it also has enough big bike feel and thrill.
    </string>
    <string name = "MT07">
        Motorcycling got a shot in the arm when Yamaha began introducing its modular, budget-priced MT range from 2013 and its mid-range, 689cc, twin cylinder version (there’s also the original 847cc MT-09 triple plus a single) has proved a deserved Europe-wide hit for its lively performance yet unintimidating manners. After being updated in 2017, like many it received another significant update for 2017 prompted by Euro5. Power is down a touch from 74 to 72.3bhp as a result (not that you’ll notice and the MT is still the ‘bounciest’ bike in the class) while it’s also been restyled to include new LED lights, given bigger brakes and a new ‘reverse LCD’ dash. More modern than the Suzuki and livelier and more nimble than the Kawasaki it’s still the lightweight, budget middleweight to beat.
    </string>
    <string name = "Trident660">
        Another newcomer for 2021 in what is quickly shaping up to be one of the most hotly contested classes of all and, by all accounts, one of the best. The all-new Trident is aimed squarely at budget-priced, entry-level middleweight roadsters such as Yamaha’s best-selling MT-07, yet is doing it in typical Triumph style. Its all-new 660cc triple produces a competitive, characterful 80bhp, it’s a brilliant handler, is, like the MT-07, easy to ride but also engaging and exciting when you want it to be. Best of all, though, the new Trident is also temptingly affordable yet somehow manages to be just that without it being obvious that any corners have been cut (although, on closer inspection, you’ll notice that the suspension is mostly unadjustable and the brakes are fairly basic two-piston Nissins). Simply, the Trident is one of the most exciting and mouth-watering additions to the class in many years.
    </string>
    <string name = "CB650R">
        The first of the transverse (or across-the-frame) four-cylinder machines here. Honda’s CB is overlooked more than most in this category but is stylish, meaty and impressive value. Originally launched as the CB650F in 2014, with 86bhp it was a little softer and novice-friendly than the riotous Hornet it succeeded but was still handsome, competent and, for bigger riders, more substantial than rival 650 twins. Updated in 2017 it got a touch more Hornet spirit by way of four extra bhp and more youthful look and was refreshed again for 2020 becoming the CB650R, with tweaks for Euro5 and stripped down ‘Neo Café’ styling to match the CB1000R, CB300R and CB125R. It may lack any particularly compelling features but the 95bhp CB is perfectly able, refined, versatile, has a touch of Honda class and, for a four, is good value.
    </string>
    <string name = "GSXS750">
        Another rebranded, updated model. Originally called the GSR750, Suzuki’s 750 fills a neat niche in this category in being a full 750 four – as based on an older, detuned GSX-R750 motor – yet still at a decent, budget-orientated price. Although hardly cutting edge, with fairly basic, non-adjustable suspension and without the latest features and electronic rider aids, with a healthy 112bhp, radial brakes and an LCD dash, the GSX-S is a more than decent, well-proportioned and well-priced roadster with enough performance to satisfy.
    </string>
    <string name = "F900R">
        New for 2020, the 900R is BMW’s enlarged, face-lifted and updated replacement for the old F800R. As such it’s part of the German firm’s middleweight twin family, alongside the F850GS adventure and F900XR adventure sport. And while the R roadster may be the less celebrated and dynamic of that trio, with a useful 103bhp, neutral, easy handling, and enviable badge and long list of optional equipment it has a classy, if slightly conservative, style many others in this class can’t match. The 900R may lack the versatility of the faired XR, the punchy performance of Yamaha’s MT (especially the 900cc version) or the bargain basement price of the Suzuki SV, but it’s a classy, all-round buy.
    </string>
    <string name = "StreetTripleR">
        The British naked middleweight triple has been the middleweight roadster class leader ever since its introduction in 2007 as a naked version of the then Daytona 675 supersports, due to its combination of lusty but flexible and accessible performance, three-cylinder character and British style. The family grew to 765cc in 2017 with base S, R and high spec RS versions then, in 2020, the S became an A2-class, 660cc offering leaving the R the most accessible with 116bhp and class-leading handling via the likes of Brembo radial brakes, multi-adjustable Showa suspension and more. Not the cheapest – if you want a more accessible middleweight Triumph triple roadster, check out the Trident – but certainly one of the best.
    </string>
    <string name = "Duke890">
        Austrian firm KTM has a deserved reputation for potent, attitude-laden roadster singles and twins and it’s latest Duke 890, which, for 2021 replaces the already brilliant and punchy Duke 790, is no exception. Although, like the 790, the new bike is a fairly diminutive roadster twin, not dissimilar to the MT-07, the enlarged parallel twin punches out an impressive 115bhp (up from the 790’s 95) along with bags of grunt and sophisticated rider electronics to make it one of the most dynamic bikes in the class. That performance is then backed up by ultra-nimble handling aided by top notch WP suspension and Brembo brakes and there’s even a higher spec R version, costing £11,999 if you really want the most this type of bike has to offer. Not for novices, maybe, of limited practicality, probably, and certainly one of the most expensive middleweight roadsters – but also one of the most exciting.
    </string>
    <string name = "Monster">
        Ducati’s all-new Monster is without doubt one of the most eagerly-awaited middleweight roadsters of 2021. An all-new bike which replaces both the previous Monster 797 and 821, it’s powered by 111bhp 937cc V-twin from the Hypermotard, gets an all-new cast aluminium frame which controversially replaces the Monster’s previously signature tubular steel trellis and comes with bang up-to-date features including electronic riding modes, a swish colour TFT dash and quality cycle parts including radial Brembo brakes. There’s even an upspecced ‘Monster +’ version with small screen and pillion seat cover, for £450 more. It’s not cheap, admittedly, being £300 more than the old 821 and a hefty £2300 more than the old entry-level 797 but as Ducati’s ‘middleweight’ Monster offering (the bigger 1200S lives on – for now) it’s undoubtedly the best.
    </string>

    <string name = "TRK502">
        On face value, legendary Italian marque Benelli, the brand right up there with Ducati and Laverda for not just its 250cc GP world championship in 1969 with Kel Carruthers but also its famous six-cylinder Sei in the mid-1970s, may have been a shadow of its former self since an abortive early-2000s revival culminated in it being taken over by the Chinese Qianjiang group in 2005. But there are increasing signs of another promising re-birth – as its TRK502 middleweight adventure bike, as launched in 2017, proves. It’s worth taking seriously, too. It comes in two forms, the stock 502 and the more rugged, off-road 502 X with longer suspension, off-road wire wheels and added protection bars but both are surprisingly decent bikes and fabulous value for money. The twin-cylinder motor produces a decent 47bhp and is both A2 licence compliant and willing and effective. Proportions-wise it’s very much a full-sized adventure, so great for taller riders, roomy for two yet still unintimidating and novice-friendly. Beefy, 50mm inverted forks and twin discs up front help it handle and stop more than adequately and, although the clocks and trimmings are a little ‘last generation’ and there’s no getting away from the fact that Chinese quality isn’t the best and the TRK is a little budget in places, you do get an awful lot for your money – especially in X trim. It might not have quite the gloss or solid reassurance of, say, Honda’s lighter, cuter, more novice-orientated and up-to-date CB500X, but the Benelli is a genuine, credible all-rounder that looks every inch the pukka adventure bike, has a classic name on its tank and comes at an almost irresistible price.
    </string>
    <string name = "CB500X">
        When first launched in 2013 alongside its roadster CB500F and sports CBR500R siblings, the 471cc, 47bhp, parallel twin X was pretty much the only credible A2-compliant adventure-styled bike. That’s now changed with the arrival of bikes such as Benelli’s TRK and more junior-still bikes such as BMW’s G310GS, but the X, thanks to repeated updates, the latest to comply with Euro5, remains the ‘go-to’ novice-friendly, affordable, middleweight adventure. The last major update in 2019 made the CB500X better than ever. Although output remained 47bhp, new valve timing, a bigger airbox and other tweaks helped make its delivery more immediate and gruntier, yet still a doddle to use. And although the tubular diamond frame was also unchanged, a larger 19-inch front wheel and revised suspension made it taller and somehow more serious without losing its novice appeal. On top of that there was revised bodywork, a new taller screen and slick new LCD clocks. The end result has ‘proper’ adventure stature and looks without losing any of its easy manageability; is an absolute piece of cake to ride yet substantial enough to be all-day capable and, though still a little basic, it has more class and polished reassurance than any of its rivals. OK, it might not be a true off-roader – but that’s true of many other adventure bikes as well – but as an introduction to adventure bikes they don’t get much better – as proven by the X’s Europe-wide sales success.
    </string>
    <string name = "Versys650">
        Bikes simply don’t get much more versatile – especially for the money – than Kawasaki’s brilliant 650 Versys – which is quite appropriate, really, as that’s what its oddball name is derived from. Larger and more substantial than A2-compliant adventures such as Honda’s CB500X, the middleweight Versys (there’s also a 1000cc, four-cylinder version) is an adventure-styled spin-off of Kawasaki’s ER6 roadster/sportster. As such, it uses the same, willing, 68bhp parallel twin motor and slightly budget tubular steel diamond frame, but with slightly longer suspension, a more upright riding position and unique bodywork including sizable fairing, adjustable touring screen and roomy, pillion-friendly saddle. The result is a middleweight that’s unintimidating yet also substantial enough for two-up touring; has performance that’s real-world usable, is surprisingly frugal yet still exciting enough for most plus handling that’s neutral, sweet steering and comfortable.
    </string>
    <string name = "VStrom650XT">
        Suzuki’s adventure-styled V-Strom 650, along with its SV650 roadster sibling, is one of the success stories of modern motorcycling – and rightly so. Like Kawasaki’s ER6/Versys family which followed, it’s a 650cc twin in a fairly budget chassis that brilliantly manages to be pretty much all things to all people – and remains so to this day. Although the original 645cc, V-twin SV650 first came out in 1999, the adventure-styled V-Strom didn’t surface until the second-generation, fuel-injected SV of 2004. It was uprated significantly in 2011 with a new look and 68bhp then got a complete makeover again in 2017 before being tweaked for Euro5 for 2021. With a flexible 71bhp, decent suspension, 12V socket, traction control, ABS and adjustable screen it’s every bit as versatile as Kawasaki’s latest Versys while the additional XT version (at £300 more) with off-road style wire wheels, hand guards and bash plate, delivers more rugged looks and a smidgeon of off-road ability (something the Versys can’t match). Sure it’s still a little basic and budget and lacks the electronic gizmos and luxury of more expensive bikes, but the latest V-Strom has everything you need, is adept and able for first timers and experienced types alike, is decently engaging and enjoyable and remains good value.
    </string>
    <string name = "Tenere700">
        Yamaha’s middleweight Ténéré (the name dates back to Yamaha’s first desert rally-inspired, big-tanked, XT600 Ténéré of 1983) was one of the most eagerly-awaited bikes of 2019. It essentially uses the universally-applauded MT-07 twin cylinder powertrain, retunes it slightly, and marries it to a chassis and all-round package inspired, not so much by middle-of-the-road adventure bikes but by full-on, Dakar Rally off-roaders. The result produces a grunty 72bhp held in a tall, slim, pukka off-road chassis complete with long-travel, multi-adjustable suspension, powerful Brembo brakes, off-road-sized wire wheels and more. As such, it’s a far more off-road-targeted adventure bike than most, in a similar way to KTM’s Adventure 790 and new 890 (see below), yet remains a decent road bike at a tempting price – although that has risen significantly since its launch. Off-road it all works brilliantly: it’s grunty, nimble, slim and agile, at least compared to most other so-called adventure bikes. On road it’s adequate with a decent screen, comfort and a flexible delivery. Yes, it lacks the slick electronics of the posher, more expensive KTM but it’s close to matching Kawasaki’s road-only Versys on the street, blows it away on the dirt and undercuts all-other genuine road/off-road adventures in terms of value. If you’re not interested in going off-road, though, you’d be much better off with Yamaha’s similarly powered Tracer 700.
    </string>
    <string name = "F850GSA">
        Adventure bike experts BMW – the German firm arguably invented the breed with its first R80G/S way back in 1980 – would be expected to be pioneers when it comes to middleweight adventure bikes and its first F800GS was exactly that when it debuted in 2008. Based on the Bavarian firm’s mid-range, 800cc parallel twin, until then only available in F800R roadster and F800ST sports-tourer forms, the GS married the perky, 85bhp twin with longer-travel, off-road suspension and wire wheels and added some adventure style bodywork all resulting in a bike that was actually a far better off-roader than its then R1200GS bigger brother thanks to its reduced weight and girth, yet was still comfortable and long-legged enough to be a decent tourer. In 2019 its adventure credentials were improved further with the introduction of this F850GS Adventure version. Based on the 94bhp, 853cc F850GS which replaced the F800GS in 2018, it shares that bike’s switchable electronic modes, impressive compromise of road and dirt ability and BMW’s usual massive list of optional extras including ESA electronically adjustable suspension, cruise control, heated grips, luggage and more, but adds a bigger, 23-litre adventure fuel tank, extended, more protective bodywork and revised ergonomics. As such, especially considering the tempting base price (which is nearly £4K cheaper than BMW’s R1250GSA) it’s arguably the ideal middleweight adventure bike. But as with many BMWs you do need to remember the cost of all those desirable extras. Add too many and you’ll be in big bike R1250GS adventure prices before you know it, which somehow defeats the idea…
    </string>
    <string name = "V85TT">
        Here’s a slightly ‘left-field’ option for you. Moto Guzzi, also known as the ‘Grand Dame’ of Italian motorcycling both for a history dating back to 1921 and a product line based on idiosyncratic, shaft drive, transversely mounted V-twins, has rarely been comfortable with adventure bikes. Its Quota in the 1990s was a heavyweight embarrassment while its more recent Stelvio still left much to be desired. But its new V85 TT more than makes up for those two with charm and a retro style all its own. By giving the TT a blend of retro scrambler style mixed with touring comfort and Guzzi’s traditional heritage appeal, Guzzi’s middleweight adventure bike offering sidesteps performance comparisons with the likes of BMW’s F850 or Triumph’s Tiger and instead concentrates on delivering acceptable versatility along with lots of quirky, character. Its signature 853cc shaft-drive V-twin is derived from that of the V9 Bobber, is flexible and charismatic and has been updated to meet Euro5 producing 80bhp for 2021. It’s upright ergonomics are all-day comfortable. It’s far less of a handful than Guzzi’s old 1200cc Stelvio and its scrambler/retro style is bang on ‘trend’ And all of that for just over £11K (the two-tone liveried version costs £200 more) makes it very tempting indeed. A fashionable, classy yet versatile and accessible all-rounder for around £11K? Guzzi might finally have got it right. Just don’t expect a lightweight off-roader, a true world-navigating adventure in the GS mould or a modern, electronics bedecked sportster such as the Tiger or Ténéré …
    </string>
    <string name = "Adventure890">
        When Yamaha introduced its new middleweight adventure bike, the 700 Ténéré, in 2019, KTM did the same with its new 790 Duke-derived 790 Adventure. Now, for 2021, the Austrian off-road specialists have gone further still, by replacing the 95bhp, high spec 790 with the larger, even more potent 103bhp 890. Power apart, the KTM differs mostly over the Yam by virtue of its more premium, lavishly equipped nature (it is £1500 more expensive, after all) and in the fact that now three versions are offered – the slightly more basic and road orientated Adventure, the higher spec and more off-roady R (for £11,999) and the limited edition, ultra exclusive ‘R Rally’ (for £18,699). All are classy and confidence-inspiring, complete with colour TFT dash, quality suspension, clever ‘saddlebag’ fuel tank which helps keep the weight low and top notch electronics including riding modes, cornering ABS and more which, in itself, lifts it a level above the Yamaha. The two R models, meanwhile,  come with top spec, fully-adjustable, 100mm longer WP suspension, taller, non-adjustable single seat (the stock version has an adjustable two-piece saddle) higher mudguard, lower, non-adjustable screen and extra ‘Rally’ rider mode. As such, in true KTM style, the Rs are significantly more serious off-roaders. KTMs being KTMs, however, even the stocker is a far more able off-roader than most rivals yet is also a more comfortable and versatile road bike as well. Unless you live most of your life in the mud, the stocker’s more than enough. If you do, the R takes middleweight adventures to another level.
    </string>
    <string name = "Tiger900">
        Leading British manufacturer Triumph has a credible recent history with middleweight adventure bikes with the Tiger 800 proving to be not just one of the best of the breed since the original was launched way back in 2010 – it’s one of the best all-round bikes, period. In 2020 these were updated again to be the Tiger 900 of which two variants are available, the road-orientated 900 GT and the more off-road 900 Rally – and both are better than ever. The key to their success is its distinctive, versatile and characterful three-cylinder engine: a longer stroke version of the Hinckley firm’s 675cc triple as used in the Daytona and Street Triple. The 94bhp unit delivers a brilliant compromise of speed and character yet having a decent dose of meaty torque as well. This unit, bolted into an upright, mid-size adventure-style chassis, has resulted in a great, comfortable, flexible, characterful all-rounder at a decent price – no wonder it’s proved so successful. The latest 900s are also fully Euro5 compliant, come in a variety of specifications including a low seat model, have all the latest riding modes and come with a slick TFT dash. The result, today, is that you can pretty much have your Tiger 900 any way you want – from budget street machine to fully-loaded off-roader which, in terms of spec, gives BMW’s GS a run for its money. Whichever way you go for, the Tiger 900’s characterful triple, classy handling and real-world practicality is almost irresistible…
    </string>
    <string name = "Multistrada950S">
        Ducati re-wrote the adventure bike rule book when it came out with the revolutionary Multistrada 1200, complete with pioneering riding modes and connected electronic suspension in 2010 and its latest version, the Multistrada V4 S, looks to have raised the bar in the big-bore adventure bike class yet again. But with an almost excessive 170bhp and a price tag now over £18K it also leaves a middle-ground which Ducati has attempted to fill with its ‘middleweight’ V-twin Multistrada 950, as introduced in 2017. That bike, with its more basic spec, almost succeeded by being affordable yet, thanks to its Hypermotard 937cc engine producing 113bhp, still had enough performance for most. This ‘S’ version, however, as introduced in 2019, is better yet coming as it does with semi-active suspension, traction control, quickshifter, riding modes and more – yet still at a price under £14K. In fact it’s such a good ‘middleweight’ it makes you wonder why you’d ever need the bigger bike. Road performance is more than enough to match the middleweight rivals here yet still carry two in touring comfort; handling, despite its larger 19in front wheel is excellent and no longer does the 950 conspicuously lack the sophisticated goodies and gizmos which made the original Multistrada 1200 so memorable. A Multistrada for the masses with all of the trinkets and toys you expect from the Ducati badge? We think so…
    </string>
</resources>